Brian Christopher Straub - Denver, Colorado

cbstraub@protonmail.com

<u>Portfolio</u> <u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Github</u>

Where I am at: I am a certified web developer with freelance experience in web design and development using the MongoDB, Express.js, React and Node.js (MERN) Stack.

Where I have been: 15 years experience in the U.S. Military and Private Military Contracting with a focus on personal protection, counterintelligence, threat protection and risk management. Regional expertise in South and Central America, Europe and the Middle East. Multi-instrumentalist with 10 years experience in music industry focusing on live music production, sound-engineering, recording and songwriting. Proficient with Pro-Tools, Abelton and analog technologies. Certified Paralegal focusing on post-conviction relief and habeas corpus, and some music industry contract law. The diversity of my life experience enables me to adapt quickly, think strategically, work calmly and effectively under pressure, solve complex issues, and work together to drive the best results for the benefit of the team. Cooking and music are my therapy.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

SSP, LLC Denver, CO - <u>Self-Employed Web Developer and Music Sound Engineer</u> Jan 2018-Present Current Web development Projects:

Ahimsattva Yoga: Implemented backend encryption and front-end design for the Authentication/Authorization landing pages of an online yoga studio and blog. Migrated codebase from React version 17 to version 18 and React Redux to Redux Toolkit; set-up a MongoDB database using express.js. Continuing responsibility for design and implementation of upcoming instructional video uploads and their associated blog pages integrated with user authentication.

<u>Gearlandia E-commerce MVP:</u> Engineered and Designed both front-end and backend using the MERN stack technologies, HTML and CSS for a simple e-commerce site focusing on outdoor adventure gear. Migrated Mongoose database connection to Mongoose version 6, implemented controller for data fetching using Express router.

React Music Blog: Static music blog site using React useContext for state management of a server-less self-contained data-set not connected to a database. Designed front-end UI to client specifications using only HTML and CSS. Migrated pixelated images from upslash.com to hi-res images from pexels.com. Continuing responsibility will be addition of contact/email page, and an e-commerce shop to sell blog related and branded merchandise.

V School - Remote- Teaching Assistant

Nov 2022 - Present

Assisting students in the full stack web development course for V School, working in Slack, Notion, Airtable and Google Workspaces on a daily basis. <u>V School</u>

Comeback Yoga - Denver, CO - Yoga Teacher

June 2019 - Present

200HR Yoga Alliance Certified Yoga Teacher providing free trauma- informed yoga classes for the military and veteran community as well as their support networks. Training in yoga for traumatic brain

injuries, adaptable yoga for amputees, yoga and meditation for post-traumatic and acute-stress. Comeback Yoga

elitefitrea - Austin, TX - Session and Live Guitarist

Jan 2018 - Present

Session and Live Guitarist for elitefitrea, an Austin based post-industrial & grunge-industrial rock band combining inspiration from bands such as NIN, Radiohead and Boards of Canada. <u>elitefitrea</u>

Yoga Teacher - Colorado - Self-employed Yoga Teacher

Jan 2009 - Jan 2018

Provided daily private and group yoga instruction focusing on Hatha and Restorative Yoga. Worked extensively providing yoga within the Colorado Department of Corrections.

Career Break May 2007- Jan 2009

Department of the Army - Iraq, Middle East - <u>Private Military Contractor</u>

Jul 2005- April 2007

Private Military Contractor conducting personnel security for civilian explosive ordnance disposal operations conducting munitions and explosives of concern (MEC) and explosive remnants of war (ERW) clearance, humanitarian mine action (HMA), and physical security and stockpile management (PSSM).

US Army - Military Police, Criminal Investigations Division, Paratrooper

Jul 1993-Nov 2004

Served in both active duty and national guard components of the U.S. Army taking part in several overseas humanitarian, peacekeeping, hazardous duty and combat related operations. Spanish linguist and Paratrooper. Extensive travel throughout Central and South America, Eastern Europe(Bosnia, Croatia, Slovenia and Hungary). Honorably discharged in 2004 after 11 years and 5 months of service.

EDUCATION:

V School - Certification - Web Development

2020-2022

Certification course gaining proficiency in React, MongoDB, Express, Node.js, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Mongoose, Postman, Slack, Json, Git/Github Version control, Axios, RESTful API's, and Agile Methodologies. Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards focused on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.JS, React, Redux, and algorithms and data structures. I created and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks by collaborating for several hours every week with a senior web developer.

Pueblo Community College - Computer and Information Sciences (CIS)

2016-2018

Certificate program gaining proficiency in Microsoft Office Suite, PowerPoint, Access Database, Microsoft Word. Advanced PC applications and Desktop Publishing. GPA 4.0

Ohio University - Athens, Ohio - Paralegal Certification

2014-2018

Certificate course training for basic Paralegal/Legal Assistant qualification. Specific areas of experience/study focus on criminal post conviction relief in the state of Colorado and Federal Habeas Corpus Law. Assisted in research and drafting of four successful post-conviction habeas corpus claims to the U.S. 10th Circuit District Court and Court of Appeals, two of which were published.

University of Colorado at Boulder - Boulder, CO - Undergraduate study

Jul 1998-May 1999

Pursuing a BA in International Relations/Affairs while serving in the active national guard. GPA 3.0, approximately 30 semester hours obtained prior to deploying to Bosnia and leaving campus.

University of Maryland Global Campus - European Division

Jul 1997- Jan 1998

German Language studies while serving overseas with active duty U.S. Army, stationed in Germany.

Additional Skills:

Registered Songwriter/Composer with Broadcast Music Inc (BMI) since 2012.

Proficient in Google Workspace, Microsoft Office Suite, Slack, Notion, Airtable

Proficient in Spanish Language

Basic comprehension and reading of German, and Brazilian Portuguese.